kidblog.org 2017-03-28

# Privacy Policy | Kidblog

**The Kidblog Inc. Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) applies to the kidblog.org website/application (the “Service”). The Service is owned and operated by Kidblog Inc., a corporation organized under Delaware law (“Kidblog,” “we,” “our”) with offices in Minneapolis, Minnesota. This Privacy Policy applies to all users and visitors of the Service, whether or not they register (“User,” “you,” “your”).

The Service is a blogging platform intended for use by teachers, students, librarians, administrators, parents, and anyone else within an educational setting.

1) Our Commitment to Privacy

This Privacy Policy explains our information practices and defines your options for controlling our use and collection of your information.

Because of technology changes or changes in privacy law, we might make changes to this policy.  If we do, we will notify you via the Service, by email, by means of a notice upon logging in to the Service, or by means of a notice on our homepage of the Service. To make our Privacy Policy easy to find, we have placed a link to it at the bottom the kidblog.org homepage.

2) The Information We Collect

This policy applies to all information collected via the Service plus any information you provide to us by email, by telephone, or in writing.

You provide personal information to us when you register to use the Service and when you request information from us. The personal information we collect from users registering for the Service includes the following:

Your name (teacher and/or school administrator)  
Display Name (this name is displayed to other users)  
Username  
Password  
Email Address  
Class Name (a “class” is a group of users defined by user registering for the Service)  
Credit Card account information (necessary to purchase our Premium Service)

The user registering for the Service can also define the members of a class and grant user access to the Service by issuing usernames and passwords to additional users.

We store all personal information submitted by users for registration purposes, and all blog text and media (images, video, embedded content) posted using the Service. If you submit additional information to us regarding the functionality of the Service or any problems you encounter, we may use this information to improve the performance of the Service, or provide customer service to you and others.

When you post or comment, other users or visitors to the Service may be able to view tis content depending on their viewing privileges. Users who register for the Service can assign viewing and usage privileges to other users.

WE URGE USERS TO EXERCISE CAUTION WHEN POSTING PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE OR OTHER PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH THE SERVICE. REMEMBER, ANY INFORMATION YOU DISCLOSE IN THESE AREAS MAY BECOME PUBLIC INFORMATION THROUGH THE ACTIONS OF ANY USER HAVING VIEWING PRIVILEGES.

In addition to the personal information you supply, we may automatically collect non-personal information to evaluate how the Service is used. We collect non-personal data to make the Service work better for users in the following ways: to improve the Service design, layout, and appearance; to provide personalization of the Service for users; and to evaluate the performance of any communication related to the Service. The technologies we use to gather this non-personal information may include IP addresses, web browser cookies, clear gifs, browser detection, and blog metadata.

3) How We Use Information

We collect personally identifiable information from registered users so that they may have secure access to the Service. Users are responsible for safeguarding their own usernames, passwords, and email addresses. If your registration or account information has been breached, you can contact us for assistance.

Our primary goal for collecting non-personal user information is to improve the performance and design of the Service.

We will not sell, rent, or lease your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent, except as set forth below.

We may use your email address to answer email we receive from you and to provide status updates for the Service.

From time to time, you may be invited to participate in optional customer surveys or contests, and Kidblog may request that you provide some or all of the above listed personally identifiable information in those surveys or contests. We use information collected through contests to contact winners and award prizes. We also use information collected from surveys to learn about our customers in order to improve our services and develop new products and services of interest to our customers.

Kidblog uses “IP addresses”, “cookies”, “clear gifs”, browser detection, and blog metadata to provide a better experience on this Service and to collect useful business information. Third party technologies such as cookies may also be used for the same purposes.

IP addresses define the Internet location of computers and help us better understand the geographic distribution of our users and manage the performance of this Service. Cookies are files placed onto the file storage system of your computer when you visit the Service so the Service will automatically recognize you each time visit the Service and deliver content specific to you. You may modify your browser preferences to accept all cookies, be notified when a cookie is set, or reject all cookies. Please consult your browser instructions for information on how to modify your choices about cookies. If you modify your browser to reject certain or all cookies, you may not be able to use certain features of the Service.

We also use a technology called “clear gifs”. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with unique identifiers that are used to track emails and online movements, helping us understand what communication campaigns and content are effective.

We detect the type of web browser you are using to optimize the performance of the Service based on the browser preferences of our users and visitors. To learn about how people use our Service we also examine blog metadata, which show the paths people take through our site and how much time they spend in certain areas.

Kidblog may contract with unaffiliated third parties to provide services for the Service, such as website and data hosting, software for Service features, customer communications, analyzing and evaluating the information we collect, and other services. When we do this, we may provide your personally identifiable information to third parties solely for purpose of providing those services; all such third parties are prohibited by contract from using such information for any other purpose.

TO THE EXTENT THAT THE INFORMATION THAT KIDBLOG COLLECTS AS PART OF THE SERVICE INCLUDES PERSONAL INFORMATION REGARDING STUDENT USERS, THE TEACHER, SCHOOL, OR SCHOOL DISTRICT RESPONSIBLE FOR SUCH STUDENT’S USE OF THE SERVICE MAY REQUEST AT ANY TIME THAT KIDBLOG DELETE ALL SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION BY SENDING AN EMAIL TO PRIVACY@KIDBLOG.ORG. EXCEPT AS NECESSARY TO PROVIDE THE SERVICE OR AS OTHERWISE SET FORTH IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY, KIDBLOG SHALL NOT SHARE, DISCLOSE, CREATE A PERSONAL PROFILE REGARDING A STUDENT USER OR OTHERWISE USE SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR ANY PURPOSE.  ALL KIDBLOG USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION REGARDING  STUDENTS SHALL BE IN CONJUNCTION WITH APPLICABLE STATE AND FEDERAL LAW, INLCUDING THE FAMILY EDUCATION RIGHTS AND PRIVACY ACT OF 1974.

4) Our Commitment to Data Security

Access to your personally identifiable information and all data you store on the Service is limited to authorized Kidblog staff and authorized service providers, and is restricted by password protection mechanisms. Kidblog protects data by encrypting web Service traffic via modern TLS (“https”) protocols, and by employing firewall technologies to prevent unauthorized access to our servers.

In the event of an unauthorized disclosure of personally identifiable information, Kidblog shall promptly notify you of such disclosure as required by applicable state and/or federal law.

5) Use of Kidblog by Children

The Service is not intended for use by unsupervised children. Only adults are authorized to register and create accounts with administrative privileges. Only accounts with administrative privileges may grant children access to the Service.

THE ADULT OR ORGANIZATION REGISTERING (OR MAINTAINING OR MODERATING) A “CLASS” OR “ORGANIZATION” AND SUBSEQUENTLY CREATING AND/OR ADDING STUDENTS/USERS TO THE ACCOUNT IS RESPONSIBLE FOR (1) OBTAINING PERMISSION OF A PARENT OR GUARDIAN OF ANY USERS UNDER 13 WHO USE THE SERVICE THROUGH A CLASS ACCOUNT; AND (2) MAKING SURE THAT THEIR USE OF THE SERVICE IS IN COMPLIANCE WITH SCHOOL GUIDELINES AND/OR STATE OR FEDERAL LAWS AND REGULATIONS.

Kidblog will not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 without consent as defined by COPPA rules and our Terms of Service.

6) Legal disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us.

We may decide to sell the business or the assets associated with the Service. In any transaction of this kind, customer information, including your personally identifiable information, may be among the assets that are transferred. It is also possible that Kidblog would sell all or substantially all of its assets and business and in such case customer information, including your personally identifiable information,  may be among the assets that are transferred. If we sell our business or its assets, you will be notified by a notice placed on the Service, or by an email to your last known email address as indicated in our records.

This Service may contain links to other websites. Kidblog is not responsible for the privacy practices of any other websites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the Service, and to read the privacy statements of each website that collects personally identifiable information. This statement of privacy practices applies only to information collected by Kidblog via the Service.

7) Your Privacy Preferences

When you sign up as a registered user of the Service you may begin receiving communications such as e-mail newsletters, product and service updates, and promotions. Users generally find this type of information useful. If you do not want to receive these updates, you must “opt-out” by unchecking the box on the registration page, or you can select the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email and follow the opt-out instructions, or send an email to privacy@kidblog.org.

8) How to Access and Correct Your Personal Data

Send us an email at privacy@kidblog.org if you want to access, review or correct your personally identifiable information collected by us. To protect your privacy and security, we may require you to log in with a user ID and password to verify your identity before granting you the right to access, review or make corrections to your personally identifiable information.

9) How to Contact Us

If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please send an email to privacy@kidblog.org or contact us by regular postal mail at Kidblog Inc., 212 Third Avenue North, Suite 478, Minneapolis, MN 55401.

Last revised: November 2, 2016

Copyright 2012-2016 © Kidblog Inc. All rights reserved.

## Classroom community with a global reach.

Students, teachers, schools, and families connect with Kidblog.
